Yes, sir. Are the cowboy boots a nod to
your affiliation for or your love for
Texas Tech?
>> [laughter]
>> He knew. He knew. Did you get them in
Lubbock?
Yeah, good day. Good day to be a
dolphin. Like what we did and
you know, excited about what we added
and I'll I'll open it up. Whatever
questions you guys have.
What do you think of Jacob Rodriguez as
this building block on defense, a little
bit a future leader of the group?
Yeah, I you know, I can't say enough
good things about Jacob and I think, you
know, more importantly
the people that have been around him for
the time that they have at Texas Tech
and the things they say about him, not
only as a football player and the
intangibles, but the type of person he
is.
Um, the tape speaks for itself. He's all
over the field. He makes plays
everywhere. His instincts are second to
none. Um, he can play in space on third
downs and he's going to help this
football team, but he's a leader. He's a
green dot guy. He'll call the defense in
time and I think he'll he'll fit really
well in the room with with uh
with Brooks [snorts] and T Dot and you
know, he'd be a great addition to the
Miami Dolphins.
Talk about the the competition. You you
talked about you want competition Sure.
>> and you do return two starters as you
just said and and now Jacob, so
you would you embrace that come you're
you know Iron sharpens iron, you know
what I mean? And then anybody in this
building that is afraid of competition
or doesn't welcome it or embrace it
shouldn't be here and that's just kind
of that's where we are. It's pretty
simple.
I want to go back to your comments about
getting bigger and more physical on this
team. You spent the first round on Kaden
Proctor and Chris Johnson, two big
players for their position. Chris Bell
is a 220 pound receiver. We go back to
the big receiver earlier in Douglas.
Just want to get you an update on how
you feel you've done to address getting
a bigger physical football team. Yeah, I
mean, I you know, I think we've done
well and and we've been intentional
making sure that
uh
who we've added regardless of the
position have
have met the measurable requirements,
but you know, we've also we want to make
sure we're adding good football players
that have the measurables, you know,
that's first and foremost. They got to
be able to play, but uh
but yeah, I've told you, you know, from
from the jump, it's important to me that
this team looks a certain way and and
moves a certain way and um
I I I believe it's big man's game.
That's not to say that there's not
really good
players in the league that are on the
smaller side that would be we know that
there's a lot of them, but yeah, we want
to build this team big, physical at all
positions and and and have a size
advantage. Were you surprised that Chris
Bell was still available at the end of
the third? Um, I wasn't sure, you know,
you never know when a guy's coming off
an injury. I'll say we were we were
really excited to add him. You know, we
I think I think most would tell you if
he wouldn't have got injured, he's
probably not sitting there anywhere
close to where we got him and it's you
know, it's one of those deals where
sounds like he's healing up great. You
know, I won't put a date on it. We would
expect him to help us this year, but you
know, it's a long-term investment. We
felt like the talent is is is is very
high. The upside is very high and it's
you know, it's a
again, long-term investment. We're kind
of you know, looking down the road. We
think we got a really good one. Kind of
getting back to Curtis' question about
competition. I mean, you take two wide
receivers in the same round. Obviously
those guys are going to be competing
from day one. Just what do you hope um,
that relationship and I guess that
competition kind of yields in the long
run? Yeah, I think, you know, I think
anytime you talk about competition,
whether it's on the field or or or in
the workplace,
it brings out the best in all of us. It
drives the the individual to excellence,
but I think there when you're going
through that, especially as rookies
together, um, you know, obviously you're
you're competing, you're wanting to to
be the best, but I think there's also a
mutual respect that that and and a bond
that happens with young players as they
go through uh the rigors of the NFL and
especially within their first year and
they do it together. Uh, it's a
brotherhood. You hear you hear players
all the time talk about family,
brotherhood and and and I would, you
know, I would foresee that developing
between those two. You know, they're
both good kids and
they're both competitors, but I think
they'll have a mutual respect for each
other and appreciation for each other
and I would think in time they'll be
they'll be rooting for each other to do
well.
So, what was that visit like to Texas
Tech? You clearly came away a little
impressed. Yeah, you know what? To be
honest with you, I most of those guys
from I didn't go through Texas Tech this
year. I saw those guys
well, I excuse me, I saw them play at
Arizona State live. I didn't go to
Lubbock, but I did see them play live at
Arizona State. Um, and then you know,
obviously throughout the
the combine and everything else, you
know, they had they had a good team.
They've done a great job out there
stocking the cupboard and getting
players that can make a difference for
them on Saturday and you know, it's a
testament to that program. They've done
a nice job, but you know, those guys
when you go to watch them play, when I
saw them play at Arizona State,
they're making plays whether you're
talking about Bailey, Rodriguez, these
receivers, the quarterback. I mean, it
it was a good football team and and the
playmakers made plays and it jumped out
to you. You could definitely see what
you needed to see in terms of when you
go scout a game live, you walk away
going
it's pretty impressive, you know.
What are you guys excited about for Will
and how was how was it to evaluate him
with such a small receiving profile
element for the years that he was at
Ohio State?
>> Sure. Yeah, it's a good question and uh
you know, Will
he he's going to be one of those guys,
he's an unsung hero. You know, he's a
grimy, dirty
bite your face off type of dude who's
going to be he's going to you know, his
he's going to be a difference maker for
us in the run game, which allows your
offense to do so many different things.
It just opens up so many doors for the
offensive coordinator way that to the
way they call the game and he's elite. I
think he's elite as a blocker. You know,
when you look when you watch the league
and see tight ends block, I think this
guy day one is on the upper echelon of
that and will only get better. Um
that doesn't make the stat sheet. That
typically doesn't make the the
highlights on ESPN, but that's okay. You
know, he's he's another culture guy who
he does everything the right way. Um, he
handles his business in the building.
His teammates are going to follow him
and he brings a physicality and a
toughness to his craft that I that I
think is unmatched. And he is, you know,
he is a um
he's a subtly good wide receiver. Now,
I'm not going to tell you that he's
going to be, you know, running away from
people and doing all those things, but
he's he's very capable underneath mid
zone. Uh, he can stretch the seam, you
know, he runs good enough to get down
the seam. He's a big body. He's got nice
hands, so he's
you know, it's not he's not a guy that
can't help you in the passing game. I
just think his his his his superpowers
is is inline blocking.
Part of your vision with with him is
part of your vision with him to line him
up at fullback from time to time? Yeah,
you know, I think you know, Bobby's
really good with those guys. I think
we'll yeah, I would imagine he'll he'll
put his hand in the dirt inline and
he'll he'll line up as an H and a
fullback and probably do some stuff on
the move. Um, he'll embrace all that and
he's good at it. So, yeah, I would
imagine we'll do a lot of that stuff
with him. Tell me a little bit more
about Jacob, you know, some of the
things that you liked about him or in
conversations and looking for
information on him, his personality.
Yeah, I you know, outgoing, um, a
leader,
uh
sets the example. You know, he leads
through his actions, so when he does
speak, it carries weight with his
teammates. Um, you know, his work ethic,
his energy, his practice habits, you
know, those are the things that are all
second to none when you talk to the
people who are around him every day.
Very, very intelligent football player,
you know, can call the defense. You
know, he's the guy you want running the
show. Um and then, you know, and then
again, just uh
his ability to communicate not only with
the coaching staff,
um but with his with his teammates. They
follow him. He's a voice. Um he has he
has a very good way about him. And then
his actions meet his words. His words
meet his actions. So, he's easy to
follow cuz you know he's going to do
what he said he's going to do. And then,
most importantly, on Saturday
now Sunday, he shows up in a big way.
You know, it's just one thing to do a
bunch of talking, but when you talk and
you don't perform
like you know, that's empty after a
while. This guy just shows up every time
he steps on the field in a big way. He's
very productive. And I think that's easy
to follow when you're his teammate. But
yeah, they they love him at the school.
I can't say enough good things. He's a
He's a very good person and he's got
great intangibles when it comes to his
craft. Sure, it's nice to have fire up
one of your best players with your
picks. Uh how much did you appreciate
Jordan Brooks uh showing up when you uh
drafted a couple of his uh Texas
>> JB's the best. He was fired up. I mean,
two two Texas Tech guys in a row. Uh who
would have thought? But yeah, he's he's
big fan of the Red Raider Nation, as you
would imagine. And um it was it was cool
to have him in the draft room. He was he
was gassed up and he got us fired up.
And uh
you know, he'll obviously be uh he'll be
a nice bridge for those guys coming
through the door to help them get
comfortable here in in South Florida.
What about Caleb Douglas? Stand out?
Yeah, good question. He um you know,
he's he's got he's a long, rangy body.
He's got some very raw athleticism. I
think I think what you'll see
um
for a tall
long long limb receiver, long legs, long
arm, he can really drop his weight. He's
got great flexibility.
Um
he's got good athleticism and ball
skills to adjust the ball in the air.
He's got to get stronger. You know, if
you're going to if you're going to try
to knock him on something, he's got to
get stronger. Uh be able to get off
press and
some of [snorts] the contested balls.
But I I you know, if you just said,
"Hey, what's one thing that jumps out?"
You know, I thought you could really see
it at his pro day and his workout. He's
uh he's pretty sudden and flexible to be
able to drop his weight and snap down
getting in and out of breaks for a long
limb athlete. So, did you come close to
making a trade up or down at any point
in this draft? Took some calls. Um but
no, I never got close. Never got close.
You know, you're always having
conversations throughout the process,
but we didn't really get close tonight.
Have there been some guys that you would
have liked to get that unfortunately
went right right before you? I'm just
wondering how much luck or It happens.
Yeah, it happens. Um
but it happens every year. You know, you
start looking at the board and you know,
it's
This is a really fun process. Obviously,
as I've stated probably more times than
you care to hear. There's you know,
there's a lot of work that goes into it.
The hard part is you just sit there and
you watching these when you have those
big gaps in between picks. You're just
watching all these guys come off the
board. You're like, "Uh
ah." You know, and then cringing. But uh
it's part of it. But yeah, it happened
and it happened tonight, you know. But
having said that um [snorts]
thrilled with how things turned out. You
know, it's uh you can't you can't fall
in love with players. You know, you it's
you you're not going to get everybody
you want. Um and often times when you
when you when you maybe want one guy and
uh
you know, we're we're always looking at
guys that we have equal value. For
whatever reason, maybe you go this way
and he gets picked and you pivot back to
this one. And then all of a sudden it's
a blessing in disguise. You know what I
mean? We're never we're never varying.
I'm never pa- you know, I'm never going
from here to here to fill a need. That
doesn't happen. We follow the board. Um
but you know, if you got like I told you
last night, you got two guys of equal
value. And then and then the need part
comes into play. And all of a sudden
somebody gets picked. Ah, you know, it
happens. So, you conscious to say Sorry,
Parker. Was there a conscious decision
to get two wide receivers on this night
or just the way the board Um what what I
would say to that is
we didn't vary from the board. We stuck
to the value. Um but we felt like we we
had to get some some some pass catchers
in there. Um we felt like that was
important. Uh again, the value of the
pass catchers where we had those ranked
was equal to, you know, the other guys
that we had on the board at the same
that we were considering. But yeah, I
would say that it was
There were we were intentional about
making sure we got some pass catchers.
I know you say that you follow the
board. You haven't selected an edge
rusher. Um is that a concern or how how
would
Yeah, you know, I mean, sure. But
like I had to remind myself 100 times
over again. Like you can't fix it all in
one weekend. It just is not going to
happen. And you got to follow the board.
And you got to take the best player
available.
Um [snorts]
and just you
you just got to know that like something
there's a you know, it could go a lot of
different ways. You could remake two
rooms. You know, we could maybe we and
I'm just talking you know, not in
specifics here. But like let's say we
redid the wide receiver room. And you
redo the edge room. But like you don't
address the secondary. And you don't
address the interior offensive line. You
don't address tight end. You know, or
you drop one in every room. I mean, it
can go 100 different ways. Um yeah, you
know, I wish I wish we had a chance to
address the edge. I like the guys we got
you know, on the roster. But uh you
know, it just it didn't happen. It
didn't fall that way. But that's okay.
You know, I I do I have faith in in Chop
and and the [snorts] rest of that crew.
And uh you know, we'll see. We got we
got some more picks tomorrow. See how it
goes. But uh
yeah, you're never going to be able to
do it all. Along those lines, do you do
you kind of look at
>> [clears throat]
>> player addition as a continuum that you
know, you do have the the cuts in in
August. You do have a trade deadline.
You do have in-season acquisitions.
Do you look at the draft as
is it? Or do you kind of think we can
always add later? 365-day-a-year
job, player acquisition. We're going to
you know, we're going to use the cut
down day. We're going to use practice
squad steals. We're going to we're going
to keep churning this thing all the way
through
to to infuse competition and and to find
players. That's how you do it. Um so,
no. This is uh this is not even close to
the end. 13 rookie class would be I
think the most here since '97. Are you
comfortable with that? Or are you very
open to
uh trimming that down to 10 or 11 or
something? I'm I'm I'm open to I mean,
I'm I'm comfortable with that. But I'm
you know, I'm I'm just going to kind of
when we get beyond the draft, I'm going
to look at the roster in totality and
just try to keep the best 90. You know
what I mean? I'm I'm open to either way.
I don't feel like I I'm I can't keep
that many rookies. We'll just keep the
best players.
>> I guess I meant like for tomorrow, are
you looking to maybe package two for one
or trade
>> you. trade for a one grade better next
year kind of thing? Um potentially.
Yeah, you know, if if we feel like
there's a player there that we covet,
I'm okay maybe using some of those picks
to go up to get maybe a better quality
player. Yeah, that's I'm I'm open to
that. Just like there's a issue with
colleges producing in-line blocking
tight ends, there seems to be an issue
with uh defensive ends that can actually
set the edge. How difficult was that in
the evaluation process for this class?
Um I will say this. That's a great
point, Omar. And what I will say is is
the ones that do it and do it well stick
out like a sore thumb. You know, it's
easy to see. Guys that are willing to
put their face on you and kind of do the
dirty work cuz
you know, it's it's become to some
degree, you know, those guys that can
get to the quarterback, they don't they
don't want to do that. They don't want
to do that stuff. So, I you know, it's
it's not difficult to evaluate. What's
what's difficult to evaluate sometimes
is the uh the ability to the flexibility
and then the the power to anchor down
and hold the point. You know, you got to
be able to see that. But the willingness
and the eagerness to come off the ball
and put your face on somebody and and do
that stuff. That jumps out to you cuz
not a lot you know, there's a lot of
those guys want to slide around the
edges. Or they just relent and get you
know, they're they're look they're
waiting for third down and go get after
the quarterback.
>> [snorts]
>> I have a question. Uh I know your pop
was a great wide receiver coach. In
light of you taking two wide receivers
in the third round, I'm curious what
were one or two things that he kind of
imparted to you about wide receiver
evaluation? Yeah, you know, it's a great
question. I am my father's son for sure
when it comes to uh what I value in a
receiver. But I've learned over the
years that um
good wide receivers come in a lot of
different you know, shapes, sizes,
packages. I I have always been privy to
you know, the Justin Jeffersons of the
world. I'll just give you an example of
somebody he can you know, somebody who's
sudden and flexible and
can can drop their weight and snap in
and out of cuts. You know what I mean?
Uh with with a dynamic quality to them.
But then you have the Mike Evans of the
world that are big, linear, climb the
ladder guys. Elite ball skills and
ability to play you know, above the rim,
so to speak. And early in early on in my
career, I was not drawn to that. I was
drawn to the to the flexible, fast,
twitchy.
Um having said that, you know, that
that's what he likes. He likes the the
elite route runners. Um I that's what I
grew up hearing and and and and
watching. And
Thank you.
All right. You have a good night. You
have a good night, too.